Ta-da!
Amazing!
Doesn't it look really cool?
It's so cool!
Oh, man!
3.3 million.
Scary, scary, scary, scary.
Hi, I'm Miku Kanemura.
This is Miku Kanamura.
Here's where I am today!
Ta-da!
I'm here at Kitamura Photographic Equipment Store!
I came here to look for a new lens.
Yes, I have a lot of opportunities to take pictures of members now.
I'm looking for a lens that is suitable for portraits.
I'm also looking for a lens that I don't have right now.
I'm hoping to have some good encounters.
In addition, here on the 6th floor, we have a selection of high-end lenses called "Leica".
I heard that they have a selection of high-end Leica lenses here on the 6th floor.
I'd like to go there to touch and feel various lenses.
I'd like to visit there.
Okay, let's get started.
This is it.
They sell different things depending on the number of times.
I guess the 3rd floor is for junk cameras and used repair shops.
And here's the Leica I'm looking for.
Yes!
is on the 6th floor, so I'm going to head there right away.
It's written here, too.
Excuse me.
Oh, hello.
Hello.
Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Moriyama, I'm Miku Kanamura.
This is my first time with Leica lenses
It's my first time, really.
I've been doing a little bit of research.
I'm looking for the Summarit 50mm
Here it is.
Please.
Yes, please.
I'm so nervous.
May I see it for a moment?
Ta-da!
Wow!
Is this all Leica?
Yes, they are.
All Leica cameras and lenses.
They're all treasures!
It's a German manufacturer that's been around for a long time.
So what's so special about them?
What is it about Leica that makes it so high class or so good?
As Mr. Kaneno mentioned earlier, Leica has been manufacturing cameras for about 100 years.
Leica has been manufacturing cameras for about 100 years.
They have a consistent shape that hasn't changed since then, and they also have a lens adapter that was released 100 years ago.
And the lenses that were released 100 years ago can be used on today's Leica with a single adapter.
You can use the lenses from 100 years ago with just one adapter.
Shifting from film cameras to digital cameras
The shape of the camera has remained unchanged over the years
The brand has been penetrated throughout the years.
I see, and the brand is the same.
This classic shape is very popular, isn't it?
Also, the manufacturing is very solid.
Even a single camera is machined from brass.
Usually, the parts are put together.
The body is made by machining the brass.
This philosophy has not changed.
Leica's coolness is still the brand name.
Leica's coolness is the brand. I see. So it's an attraction.
The ZUMA LIT that we just talked about...
There is an amazing lineup of lenses. It's true, it's written here.
This is a lens from around 1950, and it has a very gentle, soft, soft image.
The light.
When the light is backlit from the front angle
When the light is backlit from the front angle, there is a kind of halation or rainbow-like effect.
This gives the image a very unique and indescribable atmosphere.
I often take emo photos in the way we part ways now.
This is a lens that can really take those kinds of pictures.
It's nice.
But when I look at the price, it's about twice the price of the original.
There's a difference of about twice the price.
Yes, that's right.
Yes.
As I see it now, the range is from 15 to 33.
My budget today is around 100,000 yen.
If you're looking for something that fits your budget, we have a lot of them here.
I have a lot of items here.
This one is priced under 100,000 yen.
That's right, under 100,000 yen.
It's true that the soft coating on the lens is prone to scratches.
I also checked.
There was no fogging or mold on the lens.
That's great!
I was able to capture the image, and I think the scratches
I think the scratches might make the image look softer.
I think the scratches would have made the image look softer.
Then, even if you add an adapter, I think it will still cost about 100,000 yen.
I'm really curious about this.
I'd be interested in hearing about it.
Oh, you don't mind, do you?
Yes, it's okay.
Yay!
It's directly attached.
Thank you very much. I'll take him with me.
It weighs a lot.
What? Is this right?
Yes.
The red part and the white part... a little scary. Let's have you try.
Oh, no...
Focus is now on manual focus
Aperture starts here
Oh, it looks so cool
It looks really cool
But it's got a solid, heavy feel to it.
Doesn't it look really cool?
It's so cool!
I have an old silver lens.
But compared to those two lenses, it's still very good looking.
The workmanship is very detailed.
Let's look at the focus
Something close to the eye...
huh?
Huh.
oh!
Geez.
No, but it's like... it's like... it's like... it's like really, really warm.
I didn't put a filter on it or anything.
And the bokeh is really beautiful.
And the blurriness is really beautiful.
If I hadn't focused on the subject
If I hadn't focused on the subject, I would have gotten this kind of round blur.
It's very beautiful.
Yes, sir.
If you stop down a little bit to about 5.6
It's like you've drawn a picture with a crayon.
It's very gentle, but it's very moist.
Wood grain
With a snap
Like this
Stylish, isn't it?
Even just this...
It's so cool!
Great result!
I'm already satisfied with it, but I can't compare it with just one, so I'd like to recommend it to you, Mr. Maruyama.
I'll put the price aside for now, but I'd like to try this one that you recommend.
A bit smaller, a bit gentler, both for the gentle touch, and 50mm...
Are you also interested in the 35mm?
Yes, 35mm, 35mm I often shoot from a close distance...
I often take pictures from a distance with a 35mm lens.
I'm interested in the 35mm 35mm lens because I often shoot at 35mm and 35mm.
It's the first one.
It's the first perspex type.
It's very thin on the outside.
It's called a steel rim, it's called a horn, and there's a knob to turn the aperture, and there's a focus ring with a stopper.
The focusing ring has a stopper on it, so it's a very nice tool.
How old was this lens?
This is an adult, circa 1960.
This one's over 60 years old.
It's amazing, this technology.
Like this.
Bright!
I have an image that wide-angle lenses produce sharp images.
But this lens is very sharp.
It's blurry.
This was taken here at about the same distance.
But since it is a 50mm lens
so the distance is about the same.
If it were a 35mm lens
You can even see the other guy's chair.
Even my chair.
On the other hand, if we were to get really close, I don't know...
But at this distance.
If you don't get it right, it won't be in focus.
Hmm...
Hmm.
Yeah, but it's really blurry.
You see how the edges are a little soft?
I didn't do anything to it.
It would be more realistic if it were taken with a stock lens.
It's like, "Wow, this is amazing!
By the way, the price is
Oh, no!
Did I do something wrong?
Something bad just came out.
Wait a minute.
One, ten, a hundred, a thousand, ten thousand, a hundred thousand.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
3,300,000.
I'm scared, I'm scared, I'm scared
No, I know, I know, but...
It's been a valuable experience for me.
I like the 35mm.
35 mm.
Now 40 mm.
The price is still inexpensive.
I've tried some 1.5 and 1.4 brightness lenses, but I've settled on a 35mm f/3.5 lens.
This is a mode lens called Summaron, 35mm F3.5.
77,000 yen.
Oh, that's cheap!
77,000 yen is the cheapest price for Leica, isn't it?
But it's a little bit hard to adjust the focus.
The distance is the same as before.
But it's so beautiful!
Actually, it's a lens that has a pull to get deep into the image.
The reflection is also very basic.
You'd be forgiven for thinking it was a modern lens at all.
Even though it's an old lens.
This one was also focused at 3.5.
It's a little bit dark.
Yes, it is.
It takes a little bit of time to get it in focus.
But it's beautiful, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
I think it still has a little bit of Leica's distinctive warmth, doesn't it?
It's even more beautiful than normal lenses.
I wonder if I'd be happy if it were f/1 or f/2.
I think it's better to know. You can enjoy the difference in the engraving.
Yes, it is.
Ah!
Hello.
It's on the fourth floor.
There's a lot of stuff here.
Cameras from the field.
And other old cameras.
There's a lot of old cameras.
The 35mm camera I mentioned earlier.
It's a little bit...
With a bright lens.
Makoyo-san.
I'm sorry.
It's very difficult to get a good shot of a group.
The white one.
Wow, it's true!
35mm 1.4
I'm thinking 60,000 yen.
40mm, if you don't mind.
This way.
Wow.
Is this a Fuchtlender brand?
Yes, it is.
They've been around for a long time.
It's a brand that's been around for a long time.
But it went bankrupt for a while.
The brand name was used by a Japanese manufacturer
and a Japanese manufacturer, Koshina, has started up
Koshina, a Japanese manufacturer, started up the brand again.
It has a very long history.
I think this is a modern trend.
I see.
A little bit of aperture.
This way.
Oh, wow.
It's in focus... right here.
Oh, my God.
Beautiful.
Oh, wow.
Like this.
It's like the edges are curling up.
It's a model.
And the wide angle.
Take a picture here, and it'll look like this.
Take this close up.
It's good, isn't it?
You know what?
Close it down a little more.
It's wider than your field of view.
When you want to get close to the subject, but don't want to get too close.
I think it's just right.
How was it?
Well, it was very nice!
It's clearer than the Leica, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
I'm having a hard time deciding.
By the way?
The Leica?
I'm torn between the two.
Thank you for watching.
If it's Leica, I'm still thinking about Zumarit.
I'm also interested in Zumarit.
Is that 100,000 yen price pretty rare?
Yes, it is.
Oh, no! If I hear this, I'm screwed!
I can't decide!
I'm thinking that the Summarit and the 35mm Foktrendor would be better for me.
It doesn't cover anything that I already have.
It's very easy to use, and the pictures are beautiful.
And it's more practical.
Yes, it is.
Cue.
It's a matter of whether you take the practicality or the romance.
After trying it out, I felt like I wanted to try shooting 35mm.
I'm going to use this Fox Trendar this time around, and I'm going to use it as a partner again.
I'm going to be your partner again for a little bit.
With FOCTLENDER
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry, I'm having a hard time.
I'll take a picture of Roman a little further down the line.
This time the lens belongs only to the front and rear caps
The adapter is used for Sony E-mount
The adapter is for Leica M-mount lenses used with Sony E-mount lenses!
Thank you very much.
That'll be 65,300 yen.
Please.
Thank you very much.
I used it with great care
I'm done shopping.
Ta-da!
Even the cute bag!
The lens is like my little daughter!
Let me introduce them to you.
Ta-da!
It's a Foktrender 35mm 1.4.
Oh, it's so nice!
It's not too heavy.
This is the newcomer.
I've brought as many of my lenses as I can, so I'd like to introduce them here.
First of all, this is the lens that I'm wearing here.
This is the Sony g master lens 40mm 2.5.
This is the lens that I use the most.
You bought it last year?
The standard human field of view is probably 50mm, but this lens allows you to get a slightly wider field than that.
This is the lens I'm using the most right now.
I'm sure you've seen this lens before.
This is also a Sony G lens, 24-105 f/4.
This is the first lens I bought when I bought my first Sony camera.
This is one of the first lenses I bought when I bought my first Sony camera.
It's a zoom lens, so you can take pictures of things far away.
It can also take pictures of people and make the background blurry.
You can adjust the background to make it invisible.
This kind of adjustability is a good thing, and may be a good idea if you're buying this lens for the first time.
Similar lenses
Tamron Tamron brand
This one is from 28mm to 75mm F2.8.
I think there are a lot of people who have this one too.
I think it's very popular.
When did I buy this one?
I bought it about 2 years ago.
It's a Tamron third-party lens.
It's cheaper than the genuine Tamron lenses like Sigma.
It's cheaper than Sigma and stock lenses, but it's easier to use.
That's what it means.
It's a lens. This lens is also recommended for those who think that lenses are expensive.
I recommend this lens to those who think that lenses are expensive. You can get this lens at a lower price than this one.
Let's move on. Jupiter This is an old lens. Before
I introduced it when I took Mikuni's kimono off.
I introduced this lens when I took Mikuni's kimono, or rather, I bought a new lens at that time.
It is a very bright lens. It is an old Russian war lens that has a lot of flare in it, which sometimes appears when you don't intend it to.
I think it's good to use it to spice up a photo when you want to take a photo with a little bit of personality.
Manual focus
Manual focusing is a bit more difficult because you have to do it yourself.
It's a little bit difficult to adjust the focus by yourself.
But if you have one, you can use it
It can make your photos
It gives a different look to your photos
It is a very interesting lens!
Highly recommended!
Last but not least
Contax Planar
50mm
1.4
This is also often used.
I use this one a lot.
I use this a lot, too.
It looks really beautiful.
The bokeh is really beautiful.
And this is an old lens, too.
I do it by myself.
I'm going to focus on it.
It's so smooth and
And it's bright.
I want you to have it.
I want you to have one.
When I think of old lenses...
It's like this.
That's what I'm talking about.
And
I'd like to go out and shoot with the newly added lenses
I'd like to go out and shoot immediately!
So we arrived at the park.
And what a surprise!
I'd like to leave it to you to be the model.
Come here.
Hello.
I'm Rio Seimizu.
Rio, you're here.
No, no.
Thank you! I went out of my way to buy new lenses today.
I'd love to be your first model.
I'm so happy! I made it pretty!
So cute!
I'm going to have everyone take pictures of me.
She said!
So here's the first one...
I just bought a 35mm f1.4 lens from Foktrender.
I'd like to try it out.
Oh, I see... by myself.
Anyway...
Um, I'll...
I'll have you smile for me.
Great.
Okay, okay.
It's like a full body shot right now.
Great.
Let's get a little closer.
Very good. Very good.
I'll take a peek.
Oh, my God.
Nice... nice smile.
Yes, yes, yes.
Focus a little bit like this.
Okay.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
It's amazing!
The sun shining through the trees is so beautiful!
I love how smooth it is back there.
Yes it looks good
The workmanship is so beautiful.
It's like it's all blah, blah, blah.
It's so beautiful.
It's cute.
You're a good photographer.
Really?
But it makes me kind of happy.
It makes me happy.
Well, let's compare the other ones.
Here you go.
It's the Sony G lens 40mm 2.5 that I always use.
Yes.
Look this way.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So cute!
Ta-da!
Oh, what do you think?
Like this.
It looks better than before.
The reflection is more vivid than before.
It looks more three dimensional like this.
This one and this one.
Oh, it's totally different.
The color is a little more fresh.
The one before is a little heavier.
I like the shade of the trees.
Let's go in the shade.
It's nice.
The tree is a little bit taller this time.
I'm going to compare the height of the tree to see how it looks in the picture.
It's about 3 meters from here to Ryu.
That's quite a distance.
I'll tell you how much the angle of view changes.
First of all, 105mm
This is at the widest angle.
Oh, no, that's right.
I'll try tying it at 100mm.
Here we go!
Here we go. Cheese.
That's good.
Now, that's about the same as before, from the thigh up.
I wonder if it shows.
It's so beautiful.
It looks so foreign.
That's what it looks like now.
You can't see the trees.
Like right here in the foreground.
But it's more beautiful in the eyes.
It looks like this.
Here you go.
This is the 50mm Planar 1.4
This is what it looks like at the top
Yes, yes, yes...
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Nice, nice, nice.
Cute, cute, cute!
It looks like this.
It really shows off the tree.
I think it really brings out the height of the tree.
It's hard to believe we're shooting from the same spot.
Last but not least...
I'm going to try this with the 35mm lens I bought.
It's nice, but maybe it'll be good, maybe it'll come out right.
Beautiful, beautiful, nice smile, nice movement.
Here's the 35mm. It's more full body.
I think I like it a lot.
I think it's a little bit too sharp.
I think we shoot a lot of close-up shots.
I sat next to her. Look over there.
Just like that.
And then look back and smile.
The wall looks good. It doesn't look like it even though it's a close shot.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes, yes, I can do this, too.
Okay, it's good, it's good, it's good, it's good.
I thought I only had mine in the picture.
It's on the wall.
Okay, free time.
Ready, set, go!
You're looking good, fluffy.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
That's good, that's good.
So we took a lot of pictures!
Thank you very much.
You're a pro at this, aren't you?
You're a pro at taking pictures.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no!
I just took a normal picture, and you took a beautiful picture of me!
I was so happy!
I knew she was good at taking pictures!
I brought all my lenses and compared them, so if you've never taken a picture with a camera before or are curious about this lens, I hope you'll find it useful.
Please subscribe to my channel and click the "Good" button!
Subscribe to my channel and click the "Subscribe" button!